Rahul P

rahulpadmaraju@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/lrahull

Summary

Hi, I am Rahul. I am an AWS, Kubernetes and HashiCorp certified Engineer with a deep understanding of Computer science fundamentals. Currently, I am working as a Software Engineer at Chargebee focusing on DevOps and Infrastructure. 4+ years of professional industry experience in Software and Systems Engineering. Extensive experience in administering, maintaining and troubleshooting large scale systems which span across microservices in the cloud using platforms and tools like Git, AWS, Terraform, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Docker, Chef, Python, Golang and Ruby. Deep knowledge on understanding Application, Networking and System architecture in the perspective of performance and security. Extensively worked with web technologies like Java, Javascript, Spring Boot, Angular, ExpressJS and good understanding of SQL and NoSQL Databases. Curious and Willing to learn any technology or skill that is on-demand. Managed and mentored new-grads and interns in my previous roles.

Technologies:

Infrastructure: AWS EC2, AWS ECS, Kubernetes, Docker IaC: Terraform, CloudFormation, AWS SDK, AWS CLI

CI/CD: AWS CodeBuild, Jenkins(JSL - groovy), GitHub Actions, ArgoCD Configuration Management: Chef, AWS Systems Manager, Ansible

Scripting: Shell, Python, Golang, Ruby, Java, Javascript

Web: Spring Boot, Angular, NodeJs, Flask, React

Other: Leadership, Problem solving with first principals thinking, Root cause analysis, debugging and troubleshooting, managing and leading projects and team members, ability to learn on-demand, running sprint calls.

Experience

Software Engineer - Cloud Infrastructure

Chargebee

Jan 2022 - Present (11 months +)

- Developed and Implemented a fully containerised solution for a Payment processing system on ECS using Terraform.
- Implemented SecurityHub across all AWS accounts.
- Migrated Redshift clusters from DC2 to RA3 for scaling query concurrency dynamically.
- Worked as an infrastructure engineer across product teams to design and implemented their application architecture on AWS across services like ECS, EC2, CloudFront.
- Was a major part in bringing stability to the infrastructure and Terraform workflow.
- Leading multiple initiatives in Cloud Infrastructure front focusing on optimisation, security and stability
- Teaching and mentoring other team members.
- ► Technologies: AWS ECS, EKS, SQS, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, SSM, Datadog, Splunk, Terraform, SecurityHub, Config, GitHub Actions

Cloud Engineer

Coda, a Presidio Cloud Company

Jul 2020 - Jan 2022 (1 year 7 months)

- Developed a Generic Terraform module that supported the deployment of a number of AWS services based on the user inputs. This saved a lot of time and repetition for the Cloud Engineering team.
- Automated the deployment of MongoDB HA cluster on EC2 instances using Terraform and Chef Software.
- Developed a custom solution for injecting secrets into Kubernetes Pods from HashiCorp Vault in Helm.
- Writing Kitchen and Terratest for testing Terraform modules.
- Experience developing custom Kubernetes Operators.
- Architected and helped develop a custom solution for bootstrapping Chef to the Servers deployed by an Autoscaling Group.
- Extensive experience architecting and developing solutions on AWS and Kubernetes.
- Experience developing Jenkins Shared Libraries.
- Exposure to Prometheus, Grafana, Newrelic and Sumologic.
- Implemented Istio in Kubernetes clusters.
- Helping different application teams by automating the configuration management using tools like Chef, which saved a lot of time and repetition for the Database, Linux, and Windows Engineering teams.
- Teaching and mentoring other team members.
- Doing POCs on integrating various SaaS products and services to increase the efficiency and reliability of the infrastructure.
- ► Technologies used: Amazon web services(AWS), Kubernetes, Terraform, Chef, Jenkins, Docker, Python, Shell scripting, Golang(Go), Ruby, Github, Vmware Tanzu, GCP Anthos, Prometheus, Grafana, Newrelic, Sumologic

Software Engineer Intern

Coda, a Presidio Cloud Company

Aug 2019 - Jul 2020 (1 year)

- Worked on an internal project that manages employee's absence(WFH/PTO/sick) using technologies like Spring, Hibernate, Angular, AWS, Jenkins, Infrastructure as code, Docker, etc..
- Architectured the Infrastructure that can scale horizontally on AWS.
- Developed a CI/CD pipeline that deploys to 4 different environments with continuous testing and vulnerability scanning.
- Helped Design Database and Data models for Backend API.
- Worked in every part of the project(Frontend, Backend, DevOps, Cloud, Analytics)

- Learned a lot of new technologies(Spring boot, Ionic, Cloud computing, etc).
- Learned to write clean code, that is scalable and maintainable.
- ► Technologies used: Spring Boot, Angular, Ionic, AWS RDS(MySQL), AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Jenkins, AWS CloudFormation



Software Engineer Intern

Zoho

May 2019 - Jun 2019 (2 months)

- Worked on an intern management system using servlets and JSP.
- Learned the Best practices of programming and writing efficient code.
- ▶# Technologies used: C++, Java, Servlets and JSP, Bootstrap



Smart India Hackathon 2020

Feb 2019 - Mar 2019 (2 months)

- Built a web application that helps farmers to connect with other farmers and experts in the field.
- Implemented Machine Learning and computer vision to classify the diseases of the plants in real-time, based on the Leaf image data.
- Used an API that translates the complete website into major Indian languages since India is a multilingual country.
- All of the progress mentioned is done during the Hackathon which lasted for 36 hours.
- Competed against world-class programmers from across the country.
- Gained a lot of experience working with cutting edge technologies, interacting with awesome people from different universities and organizations.
- It was the world's largest Hackathon. Held by the Government of India under the scheme "Digital India".
- It was an awesome experience.
- ▶# Technologies used: Javascript(JS), Node.Js, Angular, SCSS, Heroku cloud, MySql

Full Stack Developer

Urit solutions

Sep 2018 - Dec 2018 (4 months)

- Help start a company from scratch by building an interactive website.
- Used NodeJS, Angular, SCSS for building the application.
- Designed and developed the UX and UI using angular and SCSS.
- ▶# Technologies used: Node.js, Angular, SCSS, MySql

Education



Anna University

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communications Engineering 2016 - 2020

Won a Codeathon, among 600+ other coders in our college held on HackerEarth.com

- Won a coding competition among the ECE department with 200+ participants, held by the placement cell of our college.
- Won third place among 100+ participants, presenting a paper on implementing AI in Automobiles for road safety, in the Automobile Engineering Department at Madras Institute of Technology (MIT).
- Top Ranker in Mathematics in 3 out of 4 semesters.

Licenses & Certifications

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate HashiCorp
- ☐ CKAD: Certified Kubernetes Application Developer The Linux Foundation LF-expzirfxjc
- ☐ CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator The Linux Foundation LF-rpskcggwic

Skills

Terraform • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Kubernetes • Python (Programming Language) • Docker • Git • Datadog • Splunk • Cloud Computing • Computer Networking

Honors & Awards

Presented a paper "Vehichles with Intelligent Transportation Systems" Sep 2018

In this paper, I proposed ways to improve the safety of the vehicles on the road both on the road and in the car. I talked about some ways to integrate existing technology (AI, ASICs) to improve the road safety and human-vehicle interaction, for which I was awarded the 3rd prize on the event held in Madras Institute of Technology(MIT)

Spot Award - Presidio

Feb 2021

Above and Beyond award - Presidio

May 2021

Spot Award - Presidio

Jul 2021

Adaptive Star - Chargebee

Jun 2022

Rahu	IP-	page	5
------	-----	------	---